# Simeon BABATUNDE

423 Lindsay Road, Unit 509, Clemson, SC 29631, USA | babatunde.simeon@gmail.com | +1 (864) 650-2697 http://simeonbabatunde.com

# **Career Summary**

A second year PhD student in Computer Science with a background in embedded systems, software and data engineering. Interested in building tools and technologies that enable tiny batteryless sensors to power intelligent IoT. Working towards becoming a research leader in the emerging fields of AI and IoT.

### **Professional Experience**

#### PERSIST Research Lab, Clemson University, SC

Aug. 2017 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant

- Researching efficient communication protocols for tiny batteryless sensors.
- Lead research efforts on networking for intermittently powered devices.

### School of Computing, Clemson University, SC

Aug. 2017 – Oct. 2018

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- Lead TA for CPSC 1071 (Programming Techniques and Methodology).
- Topics include program design and implementation techniques, program testing and verification, structured programming, basic data structures and analysis of algorithms using C and C++.
- Hold laboratory sessions, office hours, and coordinate other TA's in ensuring seamless content delivery.
- Lecture instructor: Catherine Hochrine.

## Venture Garden Group, Lagos, NG

Dec. 2015 – Jul. 2017

Data Engineer

- Developed and managed the first Enterprise Data Hub (EDH) built on Apache Hadoop ecosystem.
- Powered the data driven governance initiative in Nigeria through advanced analytics.
- Identified business problems to be solved with analytics and communicated findings to business decision makers.
- Won the first data science boot camp competition.

### Splashers Technologies Ltd. Lagos, NG

Aug. 2014 – Nov. 2015

Software Developer & Data Analytics Researcher

- Team Lead, Mobile Application Development. Won the Outstanding Contribution to Consolidation Goals Award, October 2015.
- Developed the first mobile solution for financial settlement among key stakeholders within the Nigerian power sector.
- Ensured new members of the mobile development team were trained and mentored on adoption and utilization of key technologies used by the team.

# **Academic Qualifications**

# • Clemson University, Clemson, SC

2017 – 2022 (Anticipated)

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

### Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, NG

Sep. 2014

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering

First Class Honors, CGPA of 4.6 on a 5.0 scale.

Second best graduating student in the department of Computer Engineering.

### • Federal Polytechnic Ilaro, NG

Sep. 2008

National Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Distinction, 3.8 CGPA on a 4.0 scale. Graduated as the Best Engineering Student.

#### Selected Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Proficient in C, Python, Java; comfortable with R, C++, and SQL.
- **Tools and Technologies:** Autodesk Eagle, TI MSP430, Software Defined Radio, Hadoop, Apache Spark, Sqoop, ELK stack (ElasticSearch-Logstash-Kibana), Hive, Pig, Kafka, Flume, Scikit-learn, StreamSets Data collector, Jupyter Notebook, Android, Nodejs, Django, Flask and LaTeX.
- Version Control Systems: Git, Subversion and Mercurial.
- **Certifications:** Data Science Specialization, Johns Hopkins University (Coursera).

# **Selected Projects**

- **UV Risk Detection and Prevention:** A wearable device that informs the user about the current and cumulative UV rays exposure level (<u>Github</u>).
- **Private Object Detection in Images using YOLO:** A private and public object detection program built on yolov3 and darknet (<u>Github</u>).
- **Packet Sniffing and Spoofing:** A sniffer and spoofing program implemented using pcap library and raw socket in C (<u>Github</u>).
- **Clemson Gameday Queue Warning System:** A customized queue warning system modeled using software verification and validation tools (AADL) and techniques (<u>Github</u>).
- **Autonomous Line Following Robot:** Built with the most basic electronic components (<u>YouTube</u>).

### Relevant Coursework

- Embedded Networked Systems - Advanced Operating Systems - Software Verification, Validation and Measurement - Translation of Programming Languages - Security in Emerging Systems

# Extracurricular Experience

- **Upsilon Pi Epsilon (CS Honor Society):** Participated in the outreach program (robotics and coding camp) for elementary students at Forest Acres Elementary, Easley.
- Association for Computing Machinery (ACM): Student member.
- **Engineers without Borders:** Active member, Clemson chapter.
- School of Computing Graduate Students Association (Clemson): Active member.